A Guide to the Papers of the Low Moor Iron Company
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Records
  - Thomas A. Mack, incl. H. G. Merry, T. A. Mack, sales, shipment correspondence, weighing, orders, difficulties in percentage mix of iron, 1897 May -1899 April; (5 folders) (Box Box 133)
  - Thomas A. Mack & Co., incl. correspondence with H. G. Merry and S. G. Cargill, sales, orders, accounts due, 1898 March -1901 Jan.; (4 folders) (Box Box 134)
  - Moore Lime Co. and other miscellaneous "M", incl. H. G. Merry - shipments, weights, sales, 1896 May -1899 Dec. (Box Box 134)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "M", incl. H. G. Merry correspondence, Mount Wolf Dynamite, Mount Carbon Co., Mille, Supply Co., 1896 March -1900 March (Box Box 134)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "T-V", incl. E. C. Means, Virginia Car Service Assoc. - on complaints about service, 1900 Feb. -1902 May (Box Box 135)
  - Thurmond Coal Co., incl. correspondence with H. G. Merry and S. G. Cargill, problems in quality of coal, railroad, cars, shipments slow or too great, etc, 1899 Sept. -1901 May (Box Box 135)
  - Tredegar Iron Works, incl. E. C. Means invoices of purchases by Low Moor, prices quoted, problems on shipment or delays, 1899 Dec. -1902 Sept. (Box Box 135)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "T", incl. correspondence of H. G. Merry, E. C. Means, S. G. Cargill, slag and cinder sold in various months at the foundry, 1900 Jan. -1906 Sept.; (2 folders) (Box Box 135)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C-T", incl. Clinton Firebrick, inventory, Thomas Automatic Shovel Co., 1894 June -1906 June (Box Box 135)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "M-W", incl. E. C. Means correspondence, McDonald Colliery, White Oak Fuel Co., 1901 Aug. -1902 Oct. (Box Box 136)
  - Thomas A. Mack, incl. E. C. Means orders, prices, invoices, sales, shipments, complaints about quality, instructions, 1901 March -1902 July; (5 folders) (Box Box 136)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C", incl. Chicago Housewrecking Co., Means, Carnegie Steel Co. - supply rails, Carey Mfg. Co., Carolina Cliffs Iron Co., Chicago Fuse Co., 1900 Jan. -1905 Dec.; (2 folders) (Box Box 137)
  - C. & O. Coal & Coke, incl. E. C. Means, shipping invoices, sales, price, difficulties, cosignees, 1905 March -Aug.; (2 folders) (Box Box 137)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A-M", incl. Marquette, Michigan, orders for plowers, etc., 1899 Dec. -1900 March (Box Box 137)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "E-M", incl. J. C. Fowle, 1900 Jan. -1906 Feb. (Box Box 137)
  - Thomas A. Mack, incl. E. C. Means correspondence, shipments, orders, accounts, etc., 1901 Feb. -April (Box Box 138)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "E", incl. H. G. Merry correspondence, Eagle Iron & Steel Co., Rush Run Coal & Coke Co., soap order, roofing, S. C. Edgar - zinc, Ensign Mfg. Co. - cars, etc., Wholesale grocers, Electric Construction & Supply Co., 1891 Sept. -1899 Sept.; (2 folders) (Box Box 138)
  - W. C. Ervin & Co., incl. orders, prices quoted - grain, hay, mill feed, etc., 1895 April -1899 Nov. (Box Box 138)
  - Queen City Supply Co. and Quaker City Rubber Co., incl. correspondence with Cargill, 1902 April -1906 March (Box Box 139)
  - Old Dominion Iron & Nail, Olive Hill, 1891 Jan. -1900 Feb. (Box Box 139)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "R," incl. correspondence with E. C. Means, Wickes, and Cargill, John Roebling - steel wire, ropes, etc. supplier, W. P. Rend - car supplier orders, coal supplier, Reese Hammond Fire Brick Co., Rand Drill, Rand Powder, mechanical suppliers, 1903 March -1904 Oct.; (3 folders) (Box Box 139)
  - Rich Patch Iron Ore Co. correspondence, incl. audits, gives precise holdings of company in physical stock, production statistics, 1903 March -1904 Jan. (Box Box 139)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "S," incl. Sully Steel & Iron Co. - suppliers, L. Schutt & Co. - engineers, Sciotto Fire Brick suppliers, Chas. A. Schieren & Co. - leather belts, etc. supplier, William B. Scaiffe - water purification for boilers, Sawyer-Mann Electric Co. - lights, E. C. Means correspondence, 1895 Dec. -1904 April; (2 folders) (Box Box 140)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C-S," incl. Means, Cargill correspondence, Cypress Lumber Co. - complete records of Low Moor purchases, Goshen Lumber - orders, Sargent, Page & Taylor, 1895 May -1904 Aug. (Box Box 140)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "Ches-Col", 1901 -1902 (Box Box 141)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "Com-Cox", 1901 -1902 (Box Box 141)
  - Covington Machine Co., 1900 -1902 (Box Box 141)
  - Covington National Bank, 1901 -1902; (2 folders) (Box Box 141)
  - Crescent Supply Co., 1901 -1902 (Box Box 141)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "Cra-Cyc ", 1898, 1901 -1902 (Box Box 141)
  - Phillips Isham, 1919 (Box Box 141)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "All-Ah", 1919, 1923, 1924, 1926 (Box Box 142)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "Bal-Buc", 1919, 1923, 1924 (Box Box 142)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "Cha-Jef", 1912, 1918 -1920, 1923-1925 (Box Box 142)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "Lac-Que", 1911, 1913, 1916, 1918 -1920, 1924, 1925 (Box Box 142)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "Rea-Rob", 1900, 1907 -1914, 1917 -1919, 1924 (Box Box 142)
  - Roanoke Bridge Co., 1910 (1911) 1912 (Box Box 142)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "Roe-Rup", 1909 -1914, 1918 (Box Box 142)
  - William C. Robinson & Son Co., 1910 -1913, 1918 (Box Box 142)
  - Robinson & Orr, 1912 (1913) 1914 (Box Box 142)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "Sch-Sull", (1910 -1914), (1919), 1920, 1924 (Box Box 142)
  - W. B. Seaton, 1910 -1912 (Box Box 142)
  - Standard Oil Co., 1907, 1909 -1911, 1913, 1914, 1919 (Box Box 142)
  - Standard Ice Co., 1910 -1914 (Box Box 142)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "Thew-Yod", (1919), 1920, 1923, (1924) (Box Box 142)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A-D, L," incl. Ashland Firebrick Co. Belknap Hardware; Covington National Bank; H. A. Dalton, Treasurer; Link Belt Co., 1916 -1924, 1926 (Box Box 143)
  - Correspondence between Dalton and Hibbert, 1916 -1917, 1924, 1926 (Box Box 143)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "B, H, J, R-S," incl. Briggs-Shaffner Co.; E. F. Houghton Co.; Chas. Hunter; Salem Foundry & Machine Works; Southern Stove Works; Sears & Roebuck & Co., 1916 -1920, 1923 -1925 (Box Box 143)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C, S, W," incl. Chesapeake & Potomac Telephone Co.; Chesapeake & Ohio Railroad; C. A. Turner; Carnegie Steel Co.; Capital City Supply Co.; Walter Wallingford & Co.; Westinghouse, Inc.; Standard Scale & Supply Co., 1908, 1915 -1919, 1923 -1924 (Box Box 143)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C," incl. Covington Machine Co.; Continental Stove Co.; Consolidation Coal Co.; Commercial Credit Co.; Commercial Coal Co.; Cincinnati Sheet Metal Roofing Co.; Cincinnati Buckeye Film Co., 1915 -1919, 1923 -1924 (Box Box 143)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C-G," incl. Hunter B. Frischkorn; Glamorgan Pipe & Foundry Co.; DeLaval Steam Turbin Co.; Crenshaw Coal Co.; H. A. Dalton, Treasurer; J. Q Dickinson & Co., 1915 -1919, 1924, 1920, 1927 (Box Box 143)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C-W", 1914 -1926 (Box Box 144)
  - F. W. H. O'Meara, Supervisor of Weighing, 1915 -1916 (Box Box 144)
  - Dalton, Isham & Howell, 1882 -1927 (Box Box 144)
  - E. W. Grice, General Supt. of Transportation, 1915 (Box Box 144)
  - E. D. Hotchkiss, Freight Traffic Manager, 1915 -1916 (Box Box 144)
  - J. B. Harris, Supt. Hinton Division, 1915 -1916 (Box Box 144)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "H", 1915 -1916 (Box Box 144)
  - C. L. Harrison, 1915 -1916 (Box Box 144)
  - Havana Central Railway Co., 1915 (Box Box 144)
  - Horace L. Haldeman, Pulaski Iron Co., 1915 -1916 (Box Box 144)
  - Charles Catlett, Chemist and Geologist, 1916 (Box Box 144)
  - Carolina Foundry & Machine Co., 1915 -1916 (Box Box 144)
  - Covington National Bank, 1914 -1916, 1926 (Box Box 144)
  - Carolina Ore Co., 1915 -1916 (Box Box 144)
  - Frank Brown, Covington District School Board, 1914 -1915 (Box Box 144)
  - Willard Park Butler, 1915 (Box Box 144)
  - The Bradstreet Co., 1915 (Box Box 144)
  - N. S. Blake, Secretary, New River Assoc., 1915 -1916 (Box Box 144)
  - C. G. Blake Co., 1915 (Box Box 144)
  - Insurance, 1915 -1916 (Box Box 144)
  - Quotations, 1916 (Box Box 144)
  - B. T. Jellison, Purchasing Agent, Richmond, 1916 (Box Box 144)
  - Meade T. Spicer, Asst. Secretary, 1916 (Box Box 144)
  - S. L. Talley, Train Master, 1915 -1916 (Box Box 144)
  - J. P. Stevens, General Supt., C. & O. Railway Co. 1915, 1915 -1916 (Box Box 144)
  - D. E. Spangler, Supt. Transportation, 1915 (Box Box 144)
  - F. S. Rockwell, Supt. (C. & O.), 1916 (Box Box 144)
  - Monteith, Manager of Mines; value of coal land; Cooke, Supt. Kay Moor; Humbert, General Manager; purchasing agents and orders, 1916 -1917 (Box Box 145)
  - Post Glover Electric Co. purchasing agent, 1915 (Box Box 145)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence with companies concerning equipment and various materials, orders, facilities, personnel (garnishee), catalog of water heater, 1909 -1926 (Box Box 145)
  - R. H. Richardson & Son - contractors, 1911 -1912 (Box Box 145)
  - Correspondence of purchasing agents, sales and orders, 1913 -1916, 1925; (2 folders) (Box Box 145)
  - Pennsylvania Rubber Co., 1915 (Box Box 145)
  - Purchasing agent and sales manager, 1915 -1916; (2 folders) (Box Box 145)
  - Pittsburgh Gage & Supply Co. purchasing agent and sales manager, 1915 -1916 (Box Box 145)
  - H. K. Porter Co. - purchasing agent correspondence, 1916 (Box Box 145)
  - Powers-Taylor Drug Co. - orders, 1916 (Box Box 145)
  - Sullivan Machine Co., 1913 (Box Box 145)
  - Suffolk Feed & Fuel Co., 1910 -1914 (Box Box 145)
  - Equipment, tax laws, 1913 -1915 (Box Box 146)
  - Bristol Co. - recording instruments, 1915 (Box Box 146)
  - Bourne Fuller Co., 1914 (Box Box 146)
  - Charles D. Carter, Jr. - insurance, 1914 -1915 (Box Box 146)
  - Capital City Supply Co. - hot water furnace, 1915 (Box Box 146)
  - Burnley Bros. - coal, 1914 -1915 (Box Box 146)
  - E. C. Means, General Manager, 1910 -1913 (Box Box 146)
  - Debevoise-Anderson Co., New England Iron Market, 1914 -1915 (Box Box 146)
  - Blue Spring Run land, orders, deliveries job applicants, injuries, 1911 -1915 (Box Box 146)
  - Primarily correspondence of Phillips Isham, 1915 -1922 (Box Box 146)
  - Ore - accounts, orders, quotations, deliveries, 1920 -1922 (Box Box 146)
  - Coal purchases, 1915 -1916 (Box Box 147)
  - Reports on Jordan Ore lands in Allegheny County, Virginia; Fenwick Mines, Roaring Run Iron Ore property; correspondence of sales and purchasing agents, 1911 -1927 (Box Box 147)
  - Coal land lease proposals, 1915 (Box Box 147)
  - Coal sales arrangements, 1915 -1916 (Box Box 147)
  - By-product coke, 1916 (Box Box 147)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A-D", incl. Atlas Powder Co., Baughman Stationery, Chesapeake & Ohio Railroad - rates, Dupont Corporation, 1908 -1927 (Box Box 147)
  - Copies of reports, article on scientific management, inventory of Kay Moor tracts, pig iron statistics, Phillips Isham, 1915, 1926 (Box Box 147)
  - Report on Kay Moor Mine; Miscellaneous "U-W", 1920 -1927 (Box Box 147)
  - W. A. Loth Stove Co., 1910 -1912 (Box Box 148)
  - H. M. Loving - coal, 1913 -1914 (Box Box 148)
  - John Lucas - paint, 1912 (Box Box 148)
  - Covington National Bank, 1912, 1914 -1915 (Box Box 148)
  - J. H. Carlisle, Supt. C. & O. Railway, 1906 -1914 (Box Box 148)
  - J. R. Cary, General Supt. of C. & O. Railway, 1906 -1912 (Box Box 148)
  - E. D. Hotchkiss - GFA C. & O. Railway, 1913 -1914 (Box Box 148)
  - Walter Wallingford & Co. - pig iron, coal and coke, 1918 (Box Box 148)
  - A. P. Gilbert AGFA C. & O. Railway, 1906 -1914 (Box Box 148)
  - Correspondence of Phillips Isham, sales agent and asst. treasurer, and J. R. Cary, general supt. of C. & O., 1910 -1919 (Box Box 148)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "L, S-T", incl. correspondence of purchasing agent, sales, assistant treasurer, general manager, 1908 -1919 (Box Box 149)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "S-T", incl. Taylor Iron & Steel Co., Somers Fitler and Todd Co., 1906 -1914 (Box Box 149)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "S", incl. Southern Telephone Co., Smith Courtney Co., L. C. Smith Typewriters, Smith & Smith, job applicants, 1907 -1914; (2 folders) (Box Box 149)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "N, S-T", incl. Southside Foundry & Machine Co., Symons Bros., F. M. Snydor - wholesale agent, Naumburg & Co., National Carbon Co., Nash Motor Co., 1909 -1920 (Box Box 149)
  - Sullivan Machinery Co., 1907 -1912 (Box Box 149)
  - Covington Machine Co., 1917 -1918 (Box Box 150)
  - Metal purchases - ladmia, zinc, 1907 -1922 (Box Box 150)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "G, P, A, M", incl. correspondence of purchasing agents, assistant treasurer, Phillips Isham, American Pig Iron Assoc. (resolution), account of Phoebus Foundry Corp., 1919 -1922 (Box Box 150)
  - Rent; note - Phoebus Foundry Corp., analysis of pig iron, general manager, Nash, Isham & Co., Phillips Isham, Assistant Treasurer, purchasing and sales agents, miscellaneous correspondence "B", 1907 -1922 (Box Box 150)
  - C. & O. Railway, incl. Lexington, Staunton, Hot Springs, C. C. Walker, Supt. of Transportation and Asst. to the General Manager; G. W. Stevens, President, 1907 -1914 (Box Box 150)
  - Burlingham Coal Co., 1914 (Box Box 150)
  - E. W. Grice, General Manager, C. & O. Railway, 1910 -1912 (Box Box 150)
  - G. W. Lipscomb & General Manager, 1909 -1914, 1919 -1920 (Box Box 151)
  - Steele & Brown (Payne) - grain, 1910 -1914 (Box Box 151)
  - Steel & Payne; Ass't. Treasurer, purchasing agents and sales manager, C. & O. Railway, 1912 -1913, 1920 (Box Box 151)
  - H. C. Skaggs, state representative, 1911 (Box Box 151)
  - Sinnamahoning Powder Mfg. Co., 1907 -1909 (Box Box 151)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "S", incl. A. Simons & Co., Shenandoah Ore Co., Miss Shipley's School, The Sintering of fine iron-bearing materials, Sherwin-Williams Co. - paint, Shimer & Co., Inc. - iron, steel, coal, coke, Charles A. Schieren Co. - tanners, William A. Shostt - claims case, 1910 -1914; (2 folders) (Box Box 151)
  - Dr. Robert H. Richards, M.I.T., 1908 -1914 (Box Box 151A)
  - Remy Electric Co., Reading Bayonee Steel Casting Co., Remington Typewriter Co., George A. Revercomb, NHY; Richmond Stove Co., Suffolk Feed & Fuel Co., Quaker City Cordage Co., 1907 -1916 (Box Box 151A)
  - The Reliance Gauge Column Co.; D. F. Rankin (hay); William C. Robinson & Son Co. - lubricants; Roanoke Hardware Co., 1915 -1916 (Box Box 151A)
  - John A. Roebling's Sons Co. - wire, 1915 -1916 (Box Box 151A)
  - Reading Steel Casting Co., Re-New Lamp Co., Queen City Supply Co., Quaker City Rubber Co., John Simmons Co. - acetylene lamps, 1915 -1916 (Box Box 151A)
  - Purchasing agent, 1915 -1916 (Box Box 151A)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A-J", incl. L. M. Hartwick, engineer; trade magazine; Iron Trade Production Co.; American Pig Iron Assoc.; American Mining Congress; H. J. Johns, Co., 1920 -1922 (Box Box 152)
  - C. & O. Railroad, incl. J. F. Bicant, supt. - C. & O.; E. D. Hotchkiss, F.T.M. and various other officials of C. & O., 1922 (Box Box 152)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "Virginia" incl. Virginia Iron, Coal, Coke Co.; Virginia Haloid Co.; Virginia Power Co.; Virginia Pig Iron Assoc., 1920 -1922 (Box Box 152)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "V-W", incl. accountant; West Virginia Coal Co.; engineer; Virginian Power Co.; Jaime Velive - importer; Wyoming Coal Sales Co., Wight & Co., Inc.; Westminister Presbyterian Church, West Virginia Coal Assoc., 1919 -1922 (Box Box 152)
  - H. A. Dalton & Lipscomb (notes at Corn Exchange Bank and monthly accounts), 1920 (Box Box 152)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "M, V", incl. Virginia-Carolina Chemical Co. pyrites cinder; Virginia Sales Agency; J. W. Monteith - Manager of Mines; Mount Hope Insurance Agency; Michelin Tire Co.; U.S. Dept. of Labor; Metallo Gasket Co., 1920 -1922 (Box Box 152)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "M", incl. Child Labor Tax Diversion - Mary F. Martin, 1919 -1920 (Box Box 152)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "L, N", incl. General Manager to Frank Lyman, New River Coal Operator's Assoc., 1922 (Box Box 153)
  - New River Coal Operators' Assoc. correspondence of general manager to various iron, steel and coal companies, 1920 -1922 (Box Box 153)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "E-V", incl. Virginia Sales Agency; Virginia Iron, Coal & Coke Co.; Frank Lyman, Eastern Coal & Export Corp.; general manager and assistant treasurer, 1920 -1922 (Box Box 153)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "L-M", incl. Matthew Addy Co.; Lake Superior Iron Ore Assoc., 1920 -1922 (Box Box 153)
  - Lake Superior Iron Ore Assoc.; Erie Iron & Steel Co.; Eaton Rhodes & Co.; Matthew Addy Co.; National Text Co.; Kay Moor, 1920 -1922 (Box Box 153)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C-M", incl. J. W. Monteith, Mgr. of Mines, T. L. Cowen, engineer; Electro Bleaching Co. general manager and various coal and iron companies; Matthew Addy Co.; Lake Superior Iron Ore Co., 1918 -1922 (Box Box 153)
  - L. F. Sullivan, Comptroller; R. T. Crawley, agent, Real Estate Dept.; other C. & O. officials, 1907 -1914 (Box Box 154)
  - S. L. Talley, T. M., Phillips Isham, 1908 -1911, 1913, 1918 -1921; (2 folders) (Box Box 154)
  - Phillips Isham, 1921 -1922; (2 folders) (Box Box 154)
  - Phillips Isham and Walter Wallingford & Co., 1922 (Box Box 154)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "W", incl. Walter Wallingford & Co. - pig iron, coal and coke alloys, market letters; weekly market letter from Woodward Iron Co., 1922 (Box Box 154A)
  - Walter Wallingford & Co., Woodward Iron Co.; market letters, 1922 (Box Box 154A)
  - C. & O. Railway: L. L. Scherer, general claim agent; Potts, passenger agent; miscellaneous correspondence "W", 1908 -1914, 1921 (Box Box 154A)
  - E. W. Grice, general supt., C. & O., 1906, 1911 (Box Box 154A)
  - Eastern Pig Iron Assoc., miscellaneous correspondence "W", 1920 -1921 (Box Box 155)
  - C. & O. - Freight Claim Agent; Rogers, Brown & Co. - claim for coke not shipped; miscellaneous correspondence "R, S"; purchasing agent and assistant treasurer, 1918 -1920 (Box Box 155)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "S", incl. C. & O., Southern Railroad, U.S. RR. Admin, purchasing agent and assistant treasurer, Lynchburg Foundry Co., J. W. Montieth, E. M. Cabell, supt., U.S. Fuel Administration, 1917 -1921 (Box Box 155)
  - General manager's circular on policy towards employees, miscellaneous correspondence "L, M, N, O", Low Moor Operators' Meeting, Ass't. Treasurer Purchasing Agent, C. & O., Treasurer's Dept. - IRS, 1919 -1920 (Box Box 155)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "P, L", incl. Phoebus Foundry Co.; Post-Glover Electrical Co.; Internal Revenue Collector - James S. Persinger, purchasing agent, ass't. treasurer, U.S. RR Admin.; C. & O.; Eaton, Rhodes & Co. - coal, coke shipments, market report, American Cyanamid Co., 1920 -1922 (Box Box 155)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "E, R, K, S, N" incl. Eaton, Rhodes & Co.; general manager to "R"; F. W. King, attorney; coke sale; Kenova Mine Car Co. - coke; Steamship Fuel Corp. - coke; Rogers, Brown & Co. - Southern Coke Market; Nash, Isham & Co., 1908 -1911, 1920 -1922 (Box Box 155)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A-T", incl. purchasing agents; Thew Co.; Hunter B. Frischkorn, Hungerford Co., 1916 -1923 (Box Box 156)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence - general manager, C. C. Cooke, supt. - weekly letter; Phillips Isham & Nash; Sales Dept., 1912 -1923 (Box Box 156)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A-V", incl. Covington Machine Co.; Davis Payne & Co.; Parkersberg Iron Co.; Barker-Jennings Hardware Co.; Thornhill Wagon Co.; Virginia Motor Car Co.; American Cart Foundry Co., 1919, 1920 (Box Box 156)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "P-S", incl. purchasing agents; proposal - spiral chute and shaker screens, Sullivan Machine Co.; F. L. Spinner - coal; N. E. Spessard - judicial appointment employers' Liability Bill, 1910, 1920 -1923 (Box Box 156)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "S" - incl. Southern Stove Works, General Manager to W. B. Seaton, 1911 -1914 (Box Box 156)
  - Correspondence of General Manager, E. U. Humbert, 1917 -1922; (2 folders) (Box Box 157)
  - General manager and Eaton, Rhodes & Co., 1922 (Box Box 157)
  - Coal age, job applications, purchasing agents, 1915 -1921 (Box Box 157)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "F-G", incl. purchasing agents, 1917 -1921 (Box Box 157)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "P-S", incl. Rife & Schoppert; Ridgeway Dynamo & Engine Co.; Lawrenceville Bronze Co.; purchasing agent; Phillips Isham; job applicants; Salem Iron Works, 1906 -1919 (Box Box 158)
  - J. F. Sanger - land sale, 1907 -1908 (Box Box 158)
  - Sankee River Cypress Lumber Co.; Frank Samuel - Happy Creek Mines; Sarco Fuel Saving & Engineering Co.; miscellaneous correspondence "L-S"; G. A. Rippetoe - Black Band Ore, 1909 -1914 (Box Box 158)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "H", incl. Huntington Supply & Equipment Co.; comparative statement of oil and waste used (Oct. - Dec. 1920); report on accidents and claims, purchasing agents and assistant treasurer (Box Box 159)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "F, S" - incl. Steele & Payne Co.; Federal Trade Commission, assistant treasurer and purchasing agent; Income Tax sorting division, job applications - bookkeeper, 1911 -1912, 1919 -1920 (Box Box 159)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C, H, G", incl. job applications, acknowledgment for calendar, assistant treasurer and purchasing agents, 1920 (Box Box 159)
  - Hunter B. Frischkorn; M. K. Frank; engineer, assistant treasurer, purchasing agent, traffic manager, Phillips Isham, 1918 -1920 (Box Box 159)
  - Phillips Isham, incl. job applications, 1918 -1920; (3 folders) (Box Box 159)
  - J. B. Harris, Supt. - C. & O. Railway, 1910 -1914 (Box Box 160)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "G, H, P", incl. Phillips Isham, J. H. Carlisle, Supt. of C. & O.; E. P. Goodwin, General Superintendent of Transportation - C. & O., 1909 -1913, 1922 (Box Box 160)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "M, P", incl Phillips Isham, Union Line - shipping delay, 1910 -1922 (Box Box 160)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "M, H, I", incl. Manufacturers Record - plan to consolidate coal and iron companies in Virginia; Contribution solicited for Independent Republican Party; C. S. Hutter - coal; Low Moor mentions uncertainly and possible strike; Ingersoll-Rand Co.- misunderstanding concerning equipment, 1911 -1922 (Box Box 160)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "H, I" - incl. Hyatt Roller Bearing Co.; W. E. Hutchinson; coal properties and consolidation plans, dividends, blast furnace operations; Italian consul pay for deceased worker; Iron Age publishing blast furnace statistics, curtailment of movement, Ingersoll-Rand Co., Indian Refining Co., 1907 -1914 (Box Box 160)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "I-J", incl. James, McKenzie & Evans - purchasing agent, shipping difficulties; Imperial Brass Mfg. Co., Industrial Traffic Assoc. - tariff; Indian Run Coal Co., 1887, 1910 -1914 (Box Box 160)
  - Phillips Isham & Co., Walter Wallingford & Co., 1907 -1918 (Box Box 160)
  - C. C. Walker, Supt. of Transportation - C. & O.; E. D. Hotchkiss, Freight Agent - C. & O., 1906 -1912 (Box Box 161)
  - E. W. Grice - general superintendent; Ladd & Baker, Inc.; R. L. Newbold & Son Co. - boiler makers, Phillips Isham, C. S. Hutter; miscellaneous correspondence "C, G, P", 1909 -1919 (Box Box 161)
  - Atlantic States Coal & Coke Co.; Grice; IRS; Atwater Kent Mfg. - brochure on ignition system; A. G. Schoonmaker & Sons - equipment; miscellaneous correspondence "A, P, R, S", 1908 -1921 (Box Box 161)